Off-season training for football.
Single leg lateral hop.
Jonsey is going to demonstrate what we mean by single leg lateral hop, which is going to work stability for you and also power.
Okay?
He is going to start on one foot, he is going to jump to the side onto the other foot and stabilize himself by landing only on one foot and then jump back and forth.
So when we are beginning this exercise and your series of exercises on the single leg, we want to take this approach of going from one leg to the other, and then we are going to work in a variation.
Do you want to show them the single leg where we do not alternate?
So now we are not going to alternate legs, he is going to still jump to the side laterally but land on the same leg.
This exercise is going to be a lot harder, so when working with this exercise, work for anywhere from eight to twelve reps on this one leg before switching over to the other leg.
If you are alternating legs, you can work on a different rep scheme.
You can work ten to fifteen reps per leg, so you can work anywhere from twenty to thirty reps for the set.
And then next we are going to do single leg forward hops.